<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Chandra Kundu | Personal Website</title>
        <link>https://chandrakundu.github.io/</link>
        <description>PhD Student at University of Central Florida</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>chandrakundu@knights.ucf.edu (Chandra Kundu)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>chandrakundu@knights.ucf.edu (Chandra Kundu)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:37:12 -0400</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://chandrakundu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Create Website with Blog using Hugo on Windows</title>
    <link>https://chandrakundu.github.io/posts/how-to-create-ai-chatbot/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:37:12 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Chandra Kundu</author>
    <guid>https://chandrakundu.github.io/posts/how-to-create-ai-chatbot/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/hugo_cover.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>In this post we will see that how to create a chatbot like ChatGPT by running Large Language Model (LLM) locally in Windows via Ollama and Open WebUI
Creating a chatbot that runs a large language model (LLM) on your local machine can be done in several ways. Here are some methods you might consider:
Using API and Programming: This approach is often difficult and time-consuming. Chatbot UI: This method requires API access from OpenAI.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>LaTeX Tips for Effective Typesetting</title>
    <link>https://chandrakundu.github.io/posts/latex-tips-for-effective-typesetting/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 20:53:47 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Chandra Kundu</author>
    <guid>https://chandrakundu.github.io/posts/latex-tips-for-effective-typesetting/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/latex_cover_photo.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>LaTeX is a powerful typesetting system used extensively for scientific documents, academic papers, and any situation which requires precision in presentation. Below are some effective tips and tricks to enhance your LaTeX typesetting, ensuring consistency and clarity in your documents.
Keeping Text Together and Box Usage Ensuring Word Cohesion with mbox and fbox To prevent LaTeX from breaking up text between lines or pages, you can use the \mbox{} command, which will keep the text inside intact regardless of formatting.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Create Website with Blog using Hugo on Windows</title>
    <link>https://chandrakundu.github.io/posts/creating-website-with-hugo-on-windows/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 00:37:12 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Chandra Kundu</author>
    <guid>https://chandrakundu.github.io/posts/creating-website-with-hugo-on-windows/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/hugo_cover.webp" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Hugo is a popular open-source static site generator (SSG) that&rsquo;s known for its speed, flexibility, and ease of use. In this post, I&rsquo;ll walk you through the process of creating a website using Hugo on Windows.
Installing Hugo Download Hugo:
To install Hugo, you can clone the repository: git clone https://github.com/gohugoio/hugo.git. Alternatively, for the latest release, visit Hugo Releases. Download the appropriate version and extract hugo.exe. Set Up Hugo:
Place hugo.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
